Sanela Radu

sanela.radu@gmail.com | Ph: 630.656.4649 | 4148 N Kimball Ave, Unit 1, Chicago, IL 60618

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Dedicated, self-motivated lab technologist with Masters level background in Biomedical Sciences. Offers strong work ethic and adaptability honed through 10+ years of clinical, research, teaching, and sales experience. Able to function as a confident leader and as an eager team player. Firmly believes in communication and the sharing of ideas towards progress and innovation. Utilizes well-developed interpersonal skills to convey care, respect, and approachability, to earn trust, and to form meaningful connections. Seeks position where past experience and values can be applied to being of service to colleagues and the public, collaborative problem-solving, and opportunities for professional growth.

EDUCATION

Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, OH

January 2015

Master of Science, Medical Physiology GPA: 4.0/4.0

The University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

June 2010

Bachelor of Arts, Biological Sciences
Specializations: Neuroscience, Endocrin

Specializations: Neuroscience, Endocrinology

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Medical Technologist, Thorek Memorial Hospital

2018

- Analyzed clinical specimens in the areas of Chemistry, Immunology, Urinalysis, Microbiology, and Molecular Biology
- Used professional judgment to manage workflow under minimal supervision during third shift
- Processed specimens appropriately based on established priorities and adapted quickly to fluctuations in work volume across multiple lab zones
- Received, tested, and stored specimens in compliance with Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs), hospital policies, and CAP/CLIA guidelines; completed CAP proficiency sample testing as needed
- Reviewed results prior to release; investigated discrepancies to determine root cause and necessary corrective actions
- Produced results consistently within expected turnaround time without sacrificing quality assurance
- Identified, documented, and reported critical values promptly
- Designed and diligently followed maintenance schedule to meet instrument requirements
- Performed daily, weekly, and bi-weekly maintenance, calibration, and QC on all automated analyzers
- Used Levey-Jennings charts to verify QC results, investigate trends, and ensure integrity of patient results
- Executed proper documentation and retention of test results, calibration/quality control measures, and instrument maintenance
- Communicated effectively when collaborating with other hospital departments and referral laboratories
- Instruments & Methodologies: Accelerate Pheno Rapid Blood Culture Detection System | Bio-Rad Bioplex 2200 | Roche Cobas e411 & c501 Chemistry Analyzers | Solana Molecular Biology Analyzer | | Cepheid GeneXpert System | Clinitek Advantus Urine Chemistry Analyzer | Urinalysis & Microscopic Examination | Microbiology | Clinical Chemistry | Immunochemistry | Molecular | Setup | Plating | PCR
- **Software:** Meditech

Laboratory Technologist, LabCorp – Litholink Corporation

2016-2018

• Promoted to Environment, Health, and Safety Officer in 2017; ensured compliance with corporate, OSHA, and EPA safety guidelines amongst all laboratory staff

- Conducted urine and blood analysis according to SOPs in a high-volume clinical laboratory; specialized in chemistry
- Performed moderate and high complexity testing for diagnostic, therapeutic, and research purposes
- Verified accuracy and validity of results via post-processing quality control, LIS autoverification, and manual review
- Maintained laboratory conditions for inspections and audits
- Performed multiple instrument comparisons, linearity, and validation on new assays and instrumentation
- Tested new reagent lots and within-lot shipments to ensure lot-to-lot comparability and adherence to QC range
- Prepared reagents used in laboratory assays and quality control procedures
- Trained new employees in laboratory area of expertise, ensuring fulfillment of competency requirements, adherence to SOPs, and compliance with regulatory agency standards
- Maintained inventory log used to monitor supply use and develop cost-saving strategies
- Instruments & Methodologies: Beckman Coulter AU680 Chemistry Analyzer | Beckman Coulter DxC 600 Synchron Clinical System | Biomek NX Automated Liquid Handlers | Mantech Automax Sampler | Tecan Freedom Evo-2 System | Beckman Coulter DTX 880 Multimode Detector | Thermo Orion EA940 pH/mV/ISE meter | Spectrophotometry | ELISA | Wet Chemistry
- Laboratory Information Management Systems: SOAR
- On the Job Training and Education: ICH GCP | HIPAA Compliance | Environment, Health, and Safety (EHS) Officer Training | Proficiency Sample Testing | CLIA & FDA Compliance | EPA & OSHA Compliance | Federal, State, and Local Government Regulatory Standards | 40 hours Continuing Education (CEUINC) credit hours

Subject Editor (Medical Physiology), Elsevier

2014-2015

- Created and prepared articles for publication in new Elsevier Biomedical Sciences Reference Module
- Performed editorial tasks using graduate-level mastery of Biomedical Sciences and source material from *Medical Physiology by Boron and Boulpaep*
- Worked independently while creating articles, proofreading for continuity & flow, formatting, selecting topicspecific figures from stock images, and identifying appropriate locations for figures, tables, and legends
- Collaborated with Case Western Reserve University faculty and students and international Elsevier executives to discuss creative ideas, set goals, and check progress

Emergency Department Scribe, Scribe America

2012-2013

Presence St. Joseph's Hospital, Elgin, IL

- Worked alongside Emergency Department Physicians to document patient assessments and medical decision making in real-time
- Wrote the History of Present Illness (HPI) and completed elements of the patient chart in compliance with HIPAA policy
- Adapted quickly and fluidly in fast-paced Level 2 adult and pediatric trauma center
- Demonstrated confidence, maturity, and exceptional ability to fulfill responsibilities during critical, high-stress situations
- Multitasked and maintained organized, detailed records for numerous patients at a time
- Facilitated communication between physicians and medical staff to strengthen teamwork and expedite treatment and disposition of patients
- Improved quality of healthcare as part of medical team by increasing physician time with patients, completing accurate documentation for hospital billing, and boosting workflow efficiency

MCAT and ACT Instructor, The Princeton Review

2011-2013

MCAT Instructor, 2012-2013

• Certified to conduct classes in subjects of General and Organic Chemistry

ACT Instructor and Private Tutor, 2011-2013

• Conducted classes for high school students covering all exam subjects, test-taking strategies, and college admissions overview; promoted to Private Tutor in 2012

- Taught effectively by creating new examples and different approaches tailored to each student's needs
- Shared new teaching ideas with coworkers to promote company success through collaboration
- Worked independently to help students set realistic goals, identify strengths, target improvement areas, administer feedback, and evaluate progress
- Scheduled and balanced multiple classes with individuals as well as groups of 10-30 students

Sales Team Leader, Best Buy

2010-2011

- Led team of Personal Computer/Home Office sales associates; ranked in top 10% of company for revenue in this department 9 consecutive months
- Trained team to effectively engage and communicate with consumers to fulfill unique needs and achieve company sales goals
- Analyzed business metrics and created monthly business plans
- Strengthened team performance through the following: continuous employee assessments and coaching, clear communication of business focus and revenue goals, development and implementation of improvement strategies, and recognition of each team member's strengths
- Reinforced company values and led by example to motivate coworkers
- Translated for Serbian and Spanish-speaking customers
- Balanced responsibilities while also holding positions as *Viewpoint Committee Member, Community Service Co-Captain*, and *Future Leaders Academy Inductee*

Research Assistant, University of Chicago

2008-2010

Department of Medicine, Section of Cardiology

Hanck Lab: Cardiac Electrophysiology

- Investigated properties of voltage-gated ion channels and effects of pharmaceutical blockers in NIH-funded study
- Employed patch-clamp and drug-profusion techniques; analyzed data using Matlab and Origin software; tissue culture

Kyle Lab: Cell and Molecular Biology

- Participated in human heart sodium channel gene cloning project
- Performed DNA construct design, spectrophotometry, PCR, gel electrophoresis, restriction-endonuclease digestions, bacterial transformations, and xenopus oocyte preparation

SKILLS

- Languages: Serbo-Croatian (native) | English (fluent) | Spanish (conversational)
- Computer Software: Microsoft Office Suite | Windows XP, Vista, 7, and 8 | SOAR | Meditech
- Web Technologies and Languages: Familiar with HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | JQuery | Python
- Independent Training / Certificates: RMOTR Python Course | ACRP Clinical Research Program Course | NIH Clinical Research Training Course
- Additional Skills: HIPAA Compliance Training | Medical Terminology | Medical Data Entry | Advanced Anatomy & Physiology | Clinical Case-Based Problem Solving | Strong Informational & Critical Listening | Teaching | Youth Mentoring | Training and Coaching | Sales and Closing Techniques

HONORS AND AWARDS

• **Scored in 86th Percentile,** National Board of Medical Examiners Physiology & Neurophysiology Subject Exams

2014

• 4th Nationally Ranked Princeton Review ACT Instructor

2012

• **Salutatorian**, Westmont High School

2006